EFTHYMIOS (THEMIS) TSAPRAZLIS

(+30) 6909528138 \diamond Athens, Greece

etsaprazlis@gmail.com \lefthymios-tsaprazlis

ABOUT ME

Senior Electrical and Computer Engineering student at NTUA focusing on Information Technology. Passionate about Machine Learning, Computer Vision and Natural Language Processing. Well-versed in programming languages such as Python and MATLAB. Strong background in mathematics, machine learning and completing projects. Currently performing research on multimodal aspects of contrastive learning as part of my diploma thesis.

EDUCATION

MEng in Electrical and Computer Engineering, National Technical University of Athens

Expected 2024

- Major in Machine Learning and Signal Processing
- Major in Computer Systems
- Minor in Software Engineering

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Computer Vision and Signal Processing Group, NTUA Robot Perception and Interaction Unit, Athena Research Center Research Assistant

Jan 2024 - present Athens, Greece

• Performing research on Lifelong Learning for robotic agents as part of the PILLAR-Robots project.

University of Texas at Austin

Research Student

Nov 2022 - present Austin TX, USA

- Machine Learning Lab (MLL) External Collaborator.
- Performing research on Contrastive Learning for VLP (Vision-Language Pretraining).

National Technical University of Athens

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Nov 2022 - present Athens, Greece

- Member of Computer Vision, Speech Communication and Signal Processing Lab (CVSP).
- Performing research on Self-Supervision and Contrastive Learning.
- Research co-advised by University of Texas at Austin.

National Centre for Scientific Research "DEMOKRITOS"

Sep 2022 - Nov 2022 Athens, Greece

Research Intern

- Member of Multimodal Analysis Group (MagCIL) of the Computational Intelligence Laboratory at Institute of Informatics and Telecommunications.
- Worked on End-to-End Multimodal Sentiment Systems.
- Created a simple framework with implementations of deep multimodal learning models for sentiment analysis.
- Performed feature extraction using various techniques and wrote training and evaluation code.

PUBLICATIONS

• Efthymios Tsaprazlis, Georgios Smyrnis, Alex Dimakis, and Petros Maragos 2023. Enhancing CLIP with a Third Modality. In NeurIPS 2023 Workshop: Self-Supervised Learning - Theory and Practice.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Workable Software Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Athens, Greece

- Member of Data Science Department.
- Performing research on visual information extraction on documents such as resumes and CVs.

SUMMER SCHOOLS

Lisbon Machine Learning School (LxMLS) 2022

Jul 2022

Instituto Superior Technico (IST)

Lisbon, Portugal

• Topics: Probability Theory & Linear Algebra, Linear Classifiers, Neural Networks, Sequence Models, Neural Structured Models, Causality.

EIT Digital Platforms for Industry 4.0

Jul 2021 - Aug 2021

Technical University of Munich

Munich, Germany

- Applied Computer Vision and Deep Learning models for video surveillance on industrial environments.
- Created a business model and business use-cases.

SKILLS

Programming Languages
Python, MATLAB /SIMULINK, C/C++, SQL,
PyTorch, Bash, Jupyter, Git, Flutter, TensorFlow

Theoretical Knowledge Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Multimodal Learning, Computer Vision,

Natural Language Processing, Contrastive Learning, Algorithms

Languages English(Fluent), Greek(Native)

VOLUNTEERING

IEEE ICASSP 2023 Student Volunteer: Served as a student volunteer in the IEEE 48th International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, and Signal Processing (ICASSP), Rhodes (2023).

IEEE Computer Society NTUA: Member of the Machine Learning team (2022 - 2023).

IEEE Robotics and Automation Society NTUA: Member of RAS (2020 - 2022).